<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-03T17:31:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Chris Cornell</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Chris Cornell</name><email>chriscornell@temple.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">Blog Beginnings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Beginnings" /><published>2018-02-01T12:41:43-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T12:41:43-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;A couple months back, halfway into my first semester at Temple, I found myself in doubt. The first Computer Science class I registered for was CIS 1166 - “Mathematical Concepts in Computing I” - a Discrete Math course. Every section of CIS 1001, the intended introductory CS course, was full by my orientation date, and I had tested out of the first programming class, CIS 1068. This landed me in a classroom full of thick-bearded upperclassmen on my first day of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first two weeks of class, I watched in horror as the 24-person roster diminished over the first two weeks to a mere 8 survivors. I found myself lost, anxious, and uncertain about my choice of major.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out and asked for advice from a family member, a soon-to-be Computer Science graduate, who took the time to give me a detailed response in which he emphasized one key goal: Make a website and use it wisely. He mentioned that to manage his own site, he runs Jekyll on a Linux VM. I thanked him and stored the advice for when I could give this new project the focus and dedication it needed. After all, I had never worked with Ruby or GitHub in the past, so this was going to be a completely new experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two mornings ago, I woke up early, grabbed a large coffee and a breakfast sandwich, and sat down in my dorm with caffeine-fueled determination. I was not going to get up until I had a functioning, attractive site up and running on Github Pages. With something such as Jekyll, this should be an easy setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Jekyll itself set up was easy enough. I created a local directory, initialized it as a GitHub repo via “git init”, cloned it to my computer, and installed Ruby (which I have never used before). After installing the necessary gems to run Jekyll on GitHub Pages, I was ready to generate the Jekyll files and view my fancy new site, and it worked! My site was fully functional on the default Jekyll theme. It took a few more commits to the ‘master’ branch to get to this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems began here: I was not a fan of the basic theme. One of the key features of Jekyll is the customization options available to the user, so a change in theme shouldn’t have been a difficult task - but it was. After some digging around, I found multiple sources from ~6 months ago claiming that GitHub Pages support is limited, and that when hosting on GitHub pages, there are only a few &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/themes/&quot;&gt;supported themes&lt;/a&gt; available. After browsing through the list, I decided on the “minimal” theme. As per the documentation, I changed my Gemfile to include “gem jekyll-theme-minimal”, and adjusted my config.yml accordingly. Jekyll is amazing, I thought to myself! I went to update my gems via “bundle install”, and lo and behold, my first roadblock presented itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Installing ffi 1.9.18 (x64-mingw32)
Gem::RuntimeRequirementNotMetError: ffi requires Ruby version &amp;lt; 2.5, &amp;gt;= 2.0. The
current ruby version is 2.5.0.
An error occurred while installing ffi (1.9.18), and Bundler cannot continue.
Make sure that `gem install ffi -v '1.9.18'` succeeds before bundling.

In Gemfile:
  github-pages was resolved to 172, which depends on
    github-pages-health-check was resolved to 1.3.5, which depends on
      typhoeus was resolved to 0.8.0, which depends on
        ethon was resolved to 0.11.0, which depends on
          ffi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annoying, but not a huge issue, right? Seems like the most recent version of ffi had not yet been updated for Ruby 2.5. Nothing a Google search can’t solve. Upon some more digging, I found a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ffi/ffi/issues/598&quot;&gt;GitHib issue on the ffi repo&lt;/a&gt; in which multiple users mentioned the same issue; Not all of the users had issues specifically while configuring Jekyll, but one or two did. A solution was posted to install ffi using the -f flag, in which users replied that it had worked. Perfect! So I went to manually force-install ffi, despite the incompatibility with the most recent version of Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ gem install ffi -f
ERROR: While executing gem ... (ArgumentError) wrong number of arguments (given 1, expected 0)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I scratched my head in confusion. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ffi/ffi/issues/598#issuecomment-354892346&quot;&gt;comment that gave this solution&lt;/a&gt; had 25 thumbs up emojis &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; 8 heart emojis - it had to work! This time, my Google-fu lead me nowhere. I decided to move to my laptop, and installed an older version of Ruby, cloned my repo, and went to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if a sign from above, I then stumbled upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/2464-use-any-theme-with-github-pages&quot;&gt;this GitHub blog post&lt;/a&gt;, announcing support for any GitHub hosted Jekyll theme.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Cornell</name><email>chriscornell@temple.edu</email></author><summary type="html">A couple months back, halfway into my first semester at Temple, I found myself in doubt. The first Computer Science class I registered for was CIS 1166 - “Mathematical Concepts in Computing I” - a Discrete Math course. Every section of CIS 1001, the intended introductory CS course, was full by my orientation date, and I had tested out of the first programming class, CIS 1068. This landed me in a classroom full of thick-bearded upperclassmen on my first day of college.</summary></entry></feed>