<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-03T00:18:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Chris Cornell</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Chris Cornell</name><email>chriscornell@temple.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">Blog Beginnings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog Beginnings" /><published>2018-02-01T12:41:43-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-01T12:41:43-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;A couple months back, halfway into my first semester at Temple, I found myself in doubt. The first Computer Science class I registered for was CIS 1166 - “Mathematical Concepts in Computing I” - a Discrete Math course. Every section of CIS 1001, the intended introductory CS course, was full by my orientation date, and I had tested out of the first programming class, CIS 1068. This landed me in a classroom full of thick-bearded upperclassmen on my first day of college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first two weeks of class, I watched in horror as the 24-person roster diminished over the first two weeks to a mere 8 survivors. I found myself lost, anxious, and uncertain about my choice of major.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out and asked for advice from a family member, a soon-to-be Computer Science graduate, who took the time to give me a detailed response in which he emphasized one key goal: Make a website and use it wisely. He mentioned that to manage his own site, he runs Jekyll on a Linux VM. I thanked him and stored the advice for when I could give this new project the focus and dedication it needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two mornings ago, I woke up early, grabbed a coffee and a breakfast sandwich, and sat down in my dorm with caffeine-fueled determination. I was not going to get up until I had a functioning, attractive site up and running on Github Pages - an attainable goal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Cornell</name><email>chriscornell@temple.edu</email></author><summary type="html">A couple months back, halfway into my first semester at Temple, I found myself in doubt. The first Computer Science class I registered for was CIS 1166 - “Mathematical Concepts in Computing I” - a Discrete Math course. Every section of CIS 1001, the intended introductory CS course, was full by my orientation date, and I had tested out of the first programming class, CIS 1068. This landed me in a classroom full of thick-bearded upperclassmen on my first day of college.</summary></entry></feed>